Finding Aid for Eclipse Jazz (University of Michigan) records, 1975-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Eclipse Jazz (University of Michigan) records 1975-1987
Eclipse Jazz (University of Michigan)
87334 Bimu F71 2
University of Michigan student organization founded to promote interest in jazz through concert and lecture series. Audio-tapes of lectures, photographs, posters, announcements of concerts, newsletters, grant files, and scattered correspondence.
2.5 linear feet
31 GB online
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the organization (donor no. 7444 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
Eclipse Jazz was a University of Michigan student organization founded to promote interest in jazz through a series of concerts and lectures.
The Eclipse Jazz records include photographs, sound records of the various lectures and concerts, posters and flyer notices of concerts, and miscellaneous administrative materials, such as grant applications, correspondence, and newsletters of their activities.
Subjects:
Eclipse Jazz (University of Michigan); Jazz--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Music--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Musicians--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Eclipse Jazz (University of Michigan); Jazz music.; Ann Arbor Art Fairs (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Michigan Union.; Musicians.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Eclipse Jazz (University of Michigan); Jazz--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Posters.; Sound recordings.
- Photographs
  - Performers, A-W, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Performers, unidentified (Box 1)
  - Eclipse staff and office (Box 1)
  - Summer concerts (Box 1)
  - Art Fair (Box 1)
- Sound recordings of lecture series, 10 in. reel-to-reel; 7 1/2 ips
  [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
  - James Dapogny, 1983 October 11, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-1-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Broadcast date 5/21/1984; Dr. James Dapogny gives lecture on piano styles of Jelly Roll Morton for Eclipse Jazz lecture Series, from the October 11th lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - James Dapogny, 1983 October 11, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-1-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Broadcast date 5/21/1984; Dr. James Dapogny gives lecture on piano styles of Jelly Roll Morton for Eclipse Jazz lecture Series. From the October 11th lecture which was held at the WUOM studies. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Richard Crawford, 1983 November 01, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-2-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Broadcast date 7/2/1984; Lecture on Duke Ellington by Dr. Richard Crawford for Eclipse Jazz lecture Series. From the November 1st. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Richard Crawford, 1983 November 01, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-2-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Broadcast date 7/9/1984; Lecture on Duke Ellington by Dr. Richard Crawford for Eclipse Jazz lecture Series. From the November 1st. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Hazen Schumacher, 1983 September 20, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-3-1-1]; mp3 file; (Dr. Hazen Schumacher discusses the development of jazz in the United States as part of the Eclipse Jazz lecture Series. From the September 20 lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Hazen Schumacher, 1983 October 04, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-4-1-1]; mp3 file; (Broadcast date 4/30/1984: Dr. Hazen Schumacher discusses the life and music of Louis Armstrong as part of the Eclipse Jazz lecture Series. From the October 4th. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Morris Lawrence Jr., 1983 September 27, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-5-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Broadcast date 5/7/1984; For the Eclipse Jazz lecture Series, Dr. Morris Lawrence Jr. discusses the origins of jazz in Africa and the U.S. and plays African live music in a live band. From the September 27th. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Morris Lawrence Jr., 1983 September 27, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-5-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Broadcast date 5/14/1984; For the Eclipse Jazz lecture Series, Dr. Morris Lawrence Jr. features some blues and plays African jazz in a live band. From the September 27th. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Richard Watson, 1983 October 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-6-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Broadcast date 6/25/1984; Dr. Richard Watson discusses bands of the big band era for Eclipse Jazz Lecture series. From the October 25th. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Richard Watson, 1983 October 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-6-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Broadcast date 6/18/1984; Dr. Richard Watson discusses Benny Goodman and plays his music for Eclipse Jazz Lecture series. From the October 25th lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Theodore Grenier, 1983 October 18, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-7-1-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; Broadcast date 6/4/1984; Mr. Theodore Grenier discusses Fats Waller and plays his music for Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series. From the October 18th. lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Theodore Grenier, 1983 October 18, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-7-2-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; Broadcast date 6/11/1984; Mr. Theodore Grenier discusses Fats Waller and plays his music for Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series. From the October 18th lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Louis Smith, 1984 January 31, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-8-1-1]; mp3 file; (Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series, possible broadcast date of February 27, 1984. Lecturer is Louis Smith discussing “Bird and Bebop” as part two of the Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series. )
  - Ed Nelson, 1984 January 24, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-9-1-1]; mp3 file; (Broadcast date 8/6/1984; For Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series, Ed Nelson discusses the development of jazz in the decades of the 50's to the 80's including Horace Silver, Les McCann, Funk and Fusion.)
  - J.C. Heard, 1983 November 22, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-10-1-1]; mp3 file; (Broadcast date 7/23/1984; J.C. Heard, jazz percussionist, plays some jazz for Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series. From the November 22nd lecture which was held at the WUOM studios. This program was prepared by Joe Behr.)
  - Kim Heron, 1984 February 07, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [87334-SR-11-1-1]; mp3 file; (Broadcast 8/27/1984; This is the second part of a lecture delivered by Kim Heron on Jazz in the 1950's as part of the Eclipse Jazz Lecture Series.)
- Other materials
  - Grant applications (Box 2)
  - Grant file (NEA) (Box 2)
  - Art Fair (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Term paper and clipping re: Eclipse Jazz (Box 2)
  - Newsletters (Box 2)
  - Programs (Box 2)
  - Posters and flyer notices for concerts (Box 3)